<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R-miss-tastic</title>
    <link>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on R-miss-tastic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/workflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/workflows/</guid>
      <description>How to handle missing values in practice ?  Missing values occur almost inevitably in most domains that handle data. Hence most data sets contain missing values, some of them might be informative. Now the question is How to handle these missing values if we want to do estimation, inference, prediction, etc.? There doesn&#39;t exist a unique and standard answer to this question since the analyses depend on different aspects of the data and several questions have to be considered before choosing a way to deal with the missing values:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/lectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/lectures/</guid>
      <description>Below you will find a selection of high-quality lectures, tutorials and labs on different aspects of missing values.
If you wish to contribute some of your own material to this platform, please feel free to contact us via the Contact form.
   General lectures   Statistical Methods for Analysis With Missing Data
 (Marie Davidian, course at NC State University, spring 2017)
    This course provides an overview of modern statistical frameworks and methods for analysis in the presence of missing data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/bibliography/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/bibliography/</guid>
      <description>On this platform we attempt to give you an overview of main references on missing values. We do not claim to gather all available references on the subject but rather to offer a peak into different fields of active research on handling missing values, allowing for an introductory reading as well as a starting point for further bibliographical research. See here for a full (and uncommented) list of references.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/rpkg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/rpkg/</guid>
      <description>R Packages This page provides introductions to popular missing data packages with small examples on how to use them. Thus the page gives more extensive information than the CRAN Task View on Missing Data, which is recommended to get a first overall overview about the CRAN missing data landscape.
You can also contribute on your own to this page and provide a short introduction to a missing data package. Take a look at this short description on how to do this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/data/</guid>
      <description>Here you will find a constantly growing list of interesting data sets which are frequently used in the R community working on missing values. These data sets can be useful to get familiar with different concepts in handling missing values and to assess the quality and performance of new methods.
If you have suggestions on other data sets which might be of interest to others, please feel free to contact us via the Contact form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/people/</guid>
      <description>People The community of people and research teams working on missing values is constantly growing but there are some researchers whose work can be considered as key contributions to the community and who provide a lot of material to different groups of interested people. Here we provide the links to their personal/group websites (in alphabetical order).
If you think you or your reaserch group should also figure on the list below feel free to contact us via the Contact form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/misc/</guid>
      <description>Some other interesting websites discussing missing values: Missing Values in Data Mining (Soft Computing and Intelligent Information Systems research group, University of Granada) Missing Data (James Carpenter, Jonathan Bartlett, London School of Hygiene &amp; Tropical Medicine) Missing Data - Software, Advice and Research on handling data with missing values (Paul von Hippel) Multiple Imputation (Stef van Buuren, currently unavailable) Imputation of missing values in Python (using scikit-learn) (scikit-learn documentation)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contribute Here is some way to contribute to the project.
 Edit the bibliography ressource; Review the Workflows available and suggest comments or improvement (or do similar workflows in python); Add data sets; Suggest ideas to organize a data challenge; Improve the FAQ  with more questions; Improve this website.  Contact If you have comments, suggestions or questions about this platform or if you wish to submit some of your own material on missing values (references, tutorials, data sets, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome!</title>
      <link>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/posts/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/posts/intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;This website provides the main methods and references for managing missing data, whether to impute, estimate or predict. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1908.04822&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; for the article introducing this project.&lt;br&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/posts/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/posts/faq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;When it comes to analyses with missing values, some questions are raised regularely during classes or seminars. We try to list the most popular questions with some elements of response. If you have another question related to the handling of missing values, feel free to contact us via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/contact/&#34;&gt;Contact form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow us on GitHub</title>
      <link>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/posts/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/posts/welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/images/missing_data_propaganda.png&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Events</title>
      <link>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/posts/events/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/posts/events/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Some upcoming and recent past events, mainly conferences, with special sessions or multiple contributions on handling missing values. (Last updated: 2019-07-18)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/packages/imputets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/packages/imputets/</guid>
      <description>Package: imputeTS
Category: Time-Series Imputation, Visualisations for Missing Data
Use-Cases: Imputation for univariate time series, Imputation of Sensor data, Visualization of time series missing data
Popularity: 
Description: Imputation (replacement) of missing values in univariate time series. Offers several imputation functions and missing data plots. Available imputation algorithms include: &amp;lsquo;Mean&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;LOCF&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Interpolation&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Moving Average&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Seasonal Decomposition&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Kalman Smoothing on Structural Time Series models&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Kalman Smoothing on ARIMA models&amp;rsquo;.
Last update:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/packages/mice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/packages/mice/</guid>
      <description>Package: mice
Category: Multiple Imputation
Use-Cases: Multiple imputation for mixes of continuous, binary, unordered categorical and ordered categorical data, Inspect the missing data, Generate simulated incomplete data
Popularity: 
Description: Multiple imputation using Fully Conditional Specification (FCS) implemented by the MICE algorithm as described in Van Buuren and Groothuis-Oudshoorn (2011) doi:10.18637/jss.v045.i03. Each variable has its own imputation model. Built-in imputation models are provided for continuous data (predictive mean matching, normal), binary data (logistic regression), unordered categorical data (polytomous logistic regression) and ordered categorical data (proportional odds).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/packages/missforest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/packages/missforest/</guid>
      <description>Package: missForest
Category: Single Imputation
Use-Cases: Single Imputation of continuous and/or categorical data.
Popularity: 
Description: The function &amp;lsquo;missForest&amp;rsquo; in this package is used to impute missing values particularly in the case of mixed-type data. It uses a random forest trained on the observed values of a data matrix to predict the missing values. It can be used to impute continuous and/or categorical data including complex interactions and non-linear relations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/packages/simputation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/packages/simputation/</guid>
      <description>Package: simputation
Category: Single Imputation, Meta-Package
Use-Cases: Use imputation algortihms of multiple packages via one interface.
Popularity: 
Description: Easy to use interfaces to a number of imputation methods that fit in the not-a-pipe operator of the &amp;lsquo;magrittr&amp;rsquo; package.
Last update: 
Algorithms:  impute_cart Decision Tree Imputation impute_const Impute by variable derivation impute_em Multivariate, model-based imputation impute_en (Robust) Linear Regression Imputation impute_hotdeck Hot deck imputation impute_knn Hot deck imputation impute_lm (Robust) Linear Regression Imputation impute_median Impute (group-wise) medians impute_mf Multivariate, model-based imputation impute_multivariate Multivariate, model-based imputation impute_pmm Hot deck imputation impute_proxy Impute by variable derivation impute_rf Decision Tree Imputation impute_rhd Hot deck imputation impute_rlm (Robust) Linear Regression Imputation impute_shd Hot deck imputation  Datasets: none</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/packages/vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/packages/vim/</guid>
      <description>Package: VIM
Category: Single Imputation, Visualisations for Missing Data
Use-Cases: Single imputation for numerical, categorical, ordered and semi-continous variables, Missing data visualizations
Popularity: 
Description: New tools for the visualization of missing and/or imputed values are introduced, which can be used for exploring the data and the structure of the missing and/or imputed values. Depending on this structure of the missing values, the corresponding methods may help to identify the mechanism generating the missing values and allows to explore the data including missing values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/packages/missmda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/packages/missmda/</guid>
      <description>Package: missMDA
Category: Single and multiple imputation
Use-Cases: Imputation of incomplete continuous, categorical or mixed datasets, &amp;hellip;
Popularity: 
Description: Imputation of incomplete continuous or categorical datasets; Missing values are imputed with a principal component analysis (PCA), a multiple correspondence analysis (MCA) model or a multiple factor analysis (MFA) model; Perform multiple imputation with and in PCA or MCA.
Last update: 
Algorithms:  Continuous data (multiple) imputation (with Principal Components Analysis) Contingency table imputation (with Correspondence Analysis) Mixed data (multiple) imputation (with Factorial Analysis of Mixed Data) Categorical data (multiple) imputation (with Multiple Correspondence Analysis) Structured data imputation (with Multiple Factor Analysis) Multilevel mixed data imputation (with Multilevel Factorial Analysis for Mixed Data) Overimputation diagnostic  Datasets:  gene geno orange ozone snorena TitanicNA vnf  Further Information:  Josse, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/packages/naniar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/packages/naniar/</guid>
      <description>Package: naniar
Category: Data Structures, Summaries, and Visualisations for Missing Data
Use-Cases: Visualization of missing values, descriptive statistics, &amp;hellip;
Popularity: 
Description: Missing values are ubiquitous in data and need to be carefully explored and handled in the initial stages of analysis. In this vignette we describe the tools in the package naniar for exploring missing data structures with minimal deviation from the common workflows of ggplot and tidy data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/bibliography/biblio_complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmisstastic.netlify.com/bibliography/biblio_complete/</guid>
      <description>A commented version of this bibliography can be found here.
  Publication type All Book Article Paper Misc    Year    Author        Citation   Year   Publication type      Yoon, J., J. Jordon, and M. Van Der Schaar. Gain: Missing data imputation using generative adversarial nets. In: arXiv preprint arXiv:1806.02920 (2018).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>